<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Kyle Tress</title>
    <link>http://kyletress.com</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 12:56:20 -0400</pubDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>September 2015</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/newsletter/september-2015</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2015 09:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/newsletter/september-2015</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As promised, no space books this month despite news that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nasa.gov/press-release/nasa-confirms-evidence-that-liquid-water-flows-on-today-s-mars&quot;&gt;scientists have discovered liquid water on the surface of Mars&lt;/a&gt;. Where there&amp;rsquo;s water, there&amp;rsquo;s usually life. See Oxford philosopher (and author of the excellent book &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1FERxdZ&quot;&gt;SuperIntelligence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) Nick Bostrom’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nickbostrom.com/extraterrestrial.pdf&quot;&gt;essay&lt;/a&gt; on why life on Mars might not be a good thing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;September was a slow reading month. That&amp;rsquo;s normal as I prepare for the upcoming skeleton season. I read some junk, a bunch of &lt;em&gt;meh&lt;/em&gt;, so I thought it would be best to revisit some old favorites this month. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1FERGxM&quot;&gt;The Historian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Elizabeth Kostova&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t resist reading a few scary books around Halloween, but &lt;em&gt;The Historian&lt;/em&gt; is special. It&amp;rsquo;s a true literary work, not just another vampire novel or historical thriller (though at times it&amp;rsquo;s both), but an intelligent and suspenseful book with excellent depth. It&amp;rsquo;s the best book about Dracula since, well, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1O8fFZ2&quot;&gt;Dracula&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. If you like vampire lore, clues hidden in mysterious books, and traipses through ancient cities, you&amp;rsquo;ll love &lt;em&gt;The Historian&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1FERRt9&quot;&gt;Performing Under Pressure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Hendrie Weisinger&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know what pressure feels like, and we envy those rare people who seem to excel when it&amp;rsquo;s on - the clutch athlete who hits the game winning home run. The pilot who lands the plane in bad weather. The surgeon who saves a life with seconds to spare. But the science shows that these people, like everyone else, actually perform &lt;em&gt;worse&lt;/em&gt; under these conditions. This book debunks the myth of the clutch performer while providing actionable tips for making the most of high pressure situations. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1GhC9yN&quot;&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Walter Isaacson&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isaacson is among my favorite biographers, but his take on Steve Jobs is controversial. I think that’s appropriate given his subject. I loved it, and I’m eager to see Aaron Sorkin’s treatment (as well as Michael Fassbender’s portrayal of Jobs) this month when the film adaptation hits theaters. It’s been four years since Steve died, and Apple hasn’t floundered in his absence. The reason is revealed in one of my favorite passages from the book — Apple itself was Steve’s greatest invention. If you enjoy Isaacson’s writing, check out &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1O8fvkp&quot;&gt;Benjamin Franklin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1FESdQk&quot;&gt;Einstein: His Life and Universe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time next month’s newsletter arrives, we’ll be a few weeks into the skeleton season. It’s hard to believe. I started this newsletter back in April, and it’s grown to nearly 30 subscribers. My goal is to reach 100 by the end of the year. If you know someone who might enjoy it, please forward it along. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for sticking with me! As always, you can reply to this email with your thoughts, likes/dislikes, and recommendations. I’ll have plenty of time over the coming months to discover and read new books. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you next month, &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kyle&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Apollo Flew to the Moon</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/how-apollo-flew-to-the-moon</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 03:25:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/how-apollo-flew-to-the-moon</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk-5</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 14:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk-5</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had anyone from Detroit stopped by Tesla Motors at this point, they would have ended up in hysterics. The sum total of the company&amp;rsquo;s automotive expertise was that a couple of the guys at Tesla really liked cars and another one had created a series of science fair projects based on technology that the automotive industry considered ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk-4</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 01:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk-4</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You always feel particularly good when the wheels lift off in Moscow,&amp;rdquo; Cantrell said. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s like, &amp;lsquo;My God. I made it.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk-3</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 01:21:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk-3</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Musk&amp;rsquo;s first interactions with the Aeronautics community were with an eclectic collection of space enthusiasts, members of a nonprofit group called the Mars Society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk-2</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 00:36:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Musk fell into the classic self-taught coder trap of writing what developers call hairballs – big, monolithic hunks of code that could go berserk for mysterious reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk-1</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 21:11:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk-1</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Elon gets into something, he develops just this different level of interest in it than other people. That is what differentiates Elon from the rest of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 01:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think there are probably too many smart people pursuing Internet stuff, finance, and law. That is part of the reason why we haven&amp;rsquo;t seen as much innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August 2015</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/newsletter/august-2015</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 09:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/newsletter/august-2015</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m sorry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just can’t stop reading about space. It must be because I’ve been watching &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://abc.go.com/shows/the-astronaut-wives-club&quot;&gt;The Astronaut Wives Club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; on Hulu, based on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1KkZQwZ&quot;&gt;New York Times bestselling book&lt;/a&gt;. This month I’ve been reading about the Space Race and the &lt;em&gt;Apollo&lt;/em&gt; program that launched us into the modern age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can think of no greater endeavor than the moon landing. The Apollo Program represents everything unique and wonderful about humanity — our curiosity, ingenuity, resolve, and insatiable desire to push our limits. I’ve learned so much about the men and women who made it happen. I’m excited to share their stories with you this month. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1WZUzPd&quot;&gt;The Right Stuff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Tom Wolfe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the seminal book on the first Americans to conquer space, &lt;em&gt;The Mercury 7&lt;/em&gt;. As a skeleton athlete, I love it for the insight Wolfe provides into why these men willingly accepted the enormous risk of their chosen profession, and the mental and physical characteristics that made them the very best. &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/rkoo4Za2Hac&quot;&gt;The Academy Award winning film adaptation is on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1KkZrKY&quot;&gt;A Man on the Moon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Andrew Chaikin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book forms the basis of the excellent Tom Hanks/Ron Howard docudrama &lt;em&gt;From the Earth to the Moon&lt;/em&gt;. I read it in 2003 shortly after the Space Shuttle Columbia tragedy, and returned to it this month to remind myself why we do these things. I think &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/g25G1M4EXrQ&quot;&gt;President Kennedy said it best&lt;/a&gt; in 1962 when he issued his famous challenge. “We choose to go to the moon in this decade and do the other things, not because they are easy, but because they are hard”. This comprehensive account of &lt;em&gt;Apollo&lt;/em&gt; will show you just how hard it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1KkZdn9&quot;&gt;The Case for Mars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Robert Zubrin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the success of &lt;em&gt;Apollo&lt;/em&gt;, what was next? For NASA, the answer was clear: Mars. But declining public interest and congressional budget cuts led to the cancellation of the program. It’s been 45 years, and we haven’t even returned to the moon, let alone Mars. Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zubrin says it’s due to excuses, poor leadership, and lack of direction. In &lt;em&gt;The Case for Mars&lt;/em&gt;, he outlines his plan for a manned mission by 2036. More importantly, he argues why we should go. &lt;em&gt;“For the science, for the challenge, for the future”&lt;/em&gt;. If an Ares mission to Mars is as successful as Apollo, the benefit will be worth the expense and the risk. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1WZUuel&quot;&gt;Elon Musk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Ashlee Vance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The excellent website &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.waitbutwhy.com&quot;&gt;Wait But Why&lt;/a&gt; recently concluded a lengthy series of posts on Elon Musk, co-founder of PayPal, founder of Tesla, SpaceX, and SolarCity. Musk not only plans to colonize Mars, he’s &lt;em&gt;actually building the technology to do so&lt;/em&gt;. Maybe NASA can’t get it done by 2036, but Musk can. This terrific biography gives us insight into the life and personality of one of the most fascinating people in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, please respond and share your thoughts with me. I love to hear about the books you’re reading. Until next month,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kyle&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/elon-musk</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2015 15:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/elon-musk</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Man on the Moon</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/a-man-on-the-moon</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2015 15:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/a-man-on-the-moon</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Right Stuff</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/the-right-stuff</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2015 15:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/the-right-stuff</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Case for Mars</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/the-case-for-mars</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 23:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/the-case-for-mars</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crooked</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/crooked</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 14:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/crooked</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A hilarious re-telling of Richard Nixon&amp;rsquo;s life &amp;ndash; with a supernatural twist. I&amp;rsquo;m a sucker for presidential biographies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July 2015</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/newsletter/july-2015</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 09:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/newsletter/july-2015</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve experienced this before. You read a book with a specific theme, place, or genre, and the next thing you know you’ve fallen down the rabbit hole and you can’t &lt;em&gt;stop&lt;/em&gt; reading about it. That happened to me this month. It kicked off with &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1IyDwNE&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Armada&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Ernest Cline. I enjoyed &lt;em&gt;Armada&lt;/em&gt;, but not as much as Cline’s first novel &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1I7LfAU&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ready Player One&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (one of my favorite books). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Armada led me to a bunch of other books in the space genre, but I’m going to skip over them (with two exceptions) since they aren’t for everyone. If you’re curious, just reply to this email and I’ll send you those, too.     &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1hbdOEW&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Martian&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Andy Weir&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am so excited to see Matt Damon portray astronaut Mark Watney in the upcoming film adaptation of this book. The Martian is about an astronaut who gets stranded on Mars, and is presumed dead. Watney must figure out a way to survive, contact Earth, and get home. Fast and fun.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1KEuPDY&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where is Everybody&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Stephen Webb&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist this book, because it covers one of my favorite thought experiments of all time. In 1950, physicist Enrico Fermi asked his colleagues a simple question. In a galaxy as large as ours (400 Billion stars), the numbers suggest we should see some sign of life - so “where is everybody?”. There are several possible solutions to the &lt;em&gt;Fermi Paradox&lt;/em&gt;, but regardless of which you prefer, the important thing is &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; you think about it. Fermi was famous for asking seemingly unanswerable questions, like “how many piano tuners are there in Chicago?”. These kinds of questions improve our skills in estimation, statistics, and logical thinking. Before you dive into it, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fermi_paradox&quot;&gt;the wikipedia page on the Fermi Paradox&lt;/a&gt;, and an introduction on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://waitbutwhy.com/2014/05/fermi-paradox.html&quot;&gt;Wait but Why blog&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1SoH2Rc&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better Than Before&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Gretchen Rubin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the Sochi Winter Olympics, I took a look at my habits and identified some areas in need of change. Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been a sucker for books on the science of habit. Enter Gretchen Rubin, author of the NYT Bestseller &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1LV8KzA&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Happiness Project&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Her latest book is a detailed look at habits, and it includes a ton of original research in how we form, change, and ultimately are our habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1KEuZer&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Antidote&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Happiness for People Who Can’t Stand Positive Thinking by &lt;em&gt;Oliver Burkeman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The power of positive thinking. We hear it from talking heads, self-help authors, and new age gurus. Inane books like &lt;em&gt;The Secret&lt;/em&gt; promote it as the key to happiness. But what if positive thinking wasn’t helping, but &lt;em&gt;hurting&lt;/em&gt; us instead? That’s the premise of this insightful, thought-provoking book. The chapter on Stoicism is alone worth the price. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Stoics say we have it all backwards. Instead of thinking about the good that could happen, we should focus on how much &lt;em&gt;worse&lt;/em&gt; things could be — and they could always be worse. Millenia ago they popularized a technique called negative visualization where one contemplates the loss of things they love, so they are better prepared to deal with it when the loss inevitably occurs. Our modern gut instinct might say this is morbid, but in reality it makes us grateful, appreciative, and understanding of the fact that we have limited control over the universe. For more on Stoicism, check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1IOZXQK&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Guide to the Good Life&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by William Irvine. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy, and see you next month!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kyle&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Armada</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/armada</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 14:25:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/armada</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I loved &lt;em&gt;Ready Player One&lt;/em&gt;, so I bought &lt;em&gt;Armada&lt;/em&gt; without a second thought. It&amp;rsquo;s a fast, fun read without much substance. Not my favorite, but it&amp;rsquo;s an enjoyable summer read. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/cdp/member-reviews/ANLVSN1MTGE9D/ref=pdp_new_read_full_review_link?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;page=1&amp;amp;sort_by=MostRecentReview#R33QHX5T591QA2&quot;&gt;My Amazon review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I use Apple Watch</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/essays/how-i-use-apple-watch</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 20:11:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/essays/how-i-use-apple-watch</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bought an Apple Watch on launch day, and since then I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten a lot of questions about it. Besides the battery life (which is way better than expected), the most common question is &amp;ldquo;what does it do?&amp;rdquo;. People want to know how the Apple Watch would fit into their lives. Inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@dmitribilgere/things-i-have-done-with-my-apple-watch-d7d31b289972&quot;&gt;this post by Dmitir Bilgier&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted to write about the main ways I&amp;rsquo;ve used my Apple Watch so far. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile boarding pass&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; On a recent trip to Colorado, I used it to go through security and to check-in at the gate. Only once did I have problems scanning the QR code. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t scan at the gate in Chicago and I had to dig for my phone, holding up the line. Sorry folks. That aside, it made the airport experience more pleasant. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timing flights&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; 
The crew says the flight is going to be 2 hours and 30 minutes. Sounds great. What time did we leave again? How much longer do we have? What time zone am I going to? I timed all my flights takeoff to touchdown so I knew exactly how much flight time was remaining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hey, Siri&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; I was a pretty regular Siri user before the Watch.  Now I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine living without it. I&amp;rsquo;m constantly asking Siri for directions, phone numbers, upcoming appointments, and reminders. Simply raising your wrist and saying &amp;ldquo;Hey Siri&amp;rdquo; activates it, which is great if you&amp;rsquo;re driving and need directions. I&amp;rsquo;ve also noticed a new feature: The &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; Siri is kind of a smart ass. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple Pay&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; Using Apple Pay on the iPhone is fun. Using it on the watch is extraordinary. I still get excited to pay with Apple Watch, if only to see the cashier&amp;rsquo;s reaction. I&amp;rsquo;ve had several tell me I&amp;rsquo;m the first to do so at their store. It feels like living in the future.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daily reminder alarms&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;m a notoriously bad eater. I have no problem eating once per day, performance effects be damned. Paired with medication that further reduces my appetite, I have to be diligent about my eating habits. I set seven daily alarms on repeat Monday - Friday to remind me to eat. Overkill? Yeah probably, but it works.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updating USADA&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; I wrote about my need to &lt;a href=&quot;/essays/usada-workflow&quot;&gt;update USADA&lt;/a&gt; on a regular basis. I automated the process with Workflow. No need to get my location or write an email. One tap and I&amp;rsquo;m done, right from the watch.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notify me to film my 1SE&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;ve been filming one second every day since 2013. Some days I forget. I allow 1SE to notify me once per day, and I immediately shoot whatever is happening at that moment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control my Apple TV&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; Using the watch as a remote is actually  easier than using the &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; Apple TV remote. I hate that thing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weather station&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; Dark Sky notifies me up to an hour before light or heavy rain. I often ride my bike to training, so this is really helpful. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Music&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; The watch has a few gigs set aside for music storage. Since the release of Apple Music, I&amp;rsquo;ve started to take advantage of this by syncing playlists directly to it and pairing it with my Beats headphones. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to warmup and workout without risking my iPhone hitting the ground.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Track and time my workout&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; One of the main reasons I bought the watch was to time my workouts (rest between sets, tempo runs, etc). Any watch could fill this role, but I like having a dedicated heart rate monitor, step counter, calorie counter, etc. The watch will almost certainly gain additional sensors over time, making it more useful in this capacity. One nitpick &amp;ndash; there is no option for setting seconds in the timer. To get a 30-second timer, you have to ask Siri.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quickly respond to messages&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how often I can respond to a message right from the watch. It&amp;rsquo;s smart, and will vary the suggested responses based on the message received. And if that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work there&amp;rsquo;s always dictation or an emoji :) .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Silent notifications&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; Probably my favorite, and the most unsung, feature of the Apple Watch is a return to blissful silence. No more chimes, beeps, or ringtones. I feel a gentle tap on my wrist when a notification arrives, and I carefully control which get through. Before the watch I&amp;rsquo;d hear three notifications for the same incoming message: one from my iPhone, one from my iPad, and another from my Mac. That drove me crazy, especially when silencing them wasn&amp;rsquo;t an option. Now everything is on silent all the time, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about missing truly important notifications. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granted, my iPhone could do nearly everything above, but the benefit of the Apple Watch is &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; it accomplishes these tasks. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t cover everything for the sake of brevity. Suffice it to say I&amp;rsquo;m finding new uses every day. It&amp;rsquo;s made a positive impact on my life, and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to see what developers do with native apps and watchOS 2. Wearables are here, and Apple is leading the way. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A workflow for updating USADA</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/essays/usada-workflow</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 16:13:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/essays/usada-workflow</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an Olympian, I&amp;rsquo;m subject to frequent random drug testing by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usada.org&quot;&gt;United States Anti-Doping Administration&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m in the &lt;em&gt;International Testing Pool&lt;/em&gt;, which means I&amp;rsquo;m required to provide USADA with a daily 60-minute time slot. Though technically I can be tested at any time, I &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; be at my designated location during this 60-minute window or I&amp;rsquo;ll receive a missed test. Three missed tests in a 12-month period could result in a ban, so it&amp;rsquo;s important that I&amp;rsquo;m diligent with my updates. The problem is I&amp;rsquo;m not always diligent, and I imagine other athletes aren&amp;rsquo;t either. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of ways to update USADA, but by far the easiest is to send an email to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:update@usada.org&quot;&gt;update@usada.org&lt;/a&gt;. Most of my teammates set a blanket 60-minute time slot for the entire quarter, then update via email as their plans change. This is simple and easy, but not without its inconveniences. First, it&amp;rsquo;s annoying to have to write the same email every time. Second, I might not have the address at my location. As a developer, I saw an opportunity to remove some of the headache and repetition for myself and other athletes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;USADA has a mobile app, but it frequently crashes and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to use&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Their website isn&amp;rsquo;t much better. There&amp;rsquo;s no public API, so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t create my own app. I wanted the simplicity of email updates with the convenience of a &amp;lsquo;native&amp;rsquo; mobile app. Enter &lt;a href=&quot;https://workflow.is&quot;&gt;Workflow&lt;/a&gt;.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Workflow App&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Workflow is an app that bills itself as &amp;lsquo;powerful automation made simple&amp;rsquo;. Federico Viticci of MacStories.net wrote &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macstories.net/reviews/workflow-review-integrated-automation-for-ios-8/&quot;&gt;a terrific review of Workflow&lt;/a&gt;, so I won&amp;rsquo;t retread that ground here. Suffice it to say, Workflow makes it possible to automate repetitive tasks by taking advantage of native iOS functionality. A workflow can be saved on the home screen of your device and act as its own little native app. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Update USADA Workflow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given my requirements, setting up the workflow was easy. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get the current location and save it as a variable &lt;code&gt;location&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask the user for a 60-minute time slot, and save it as &lt;code&gt;timeslot&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create an email to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:update@usada.org&quot;&gt;update@usada.org&lt;/a&gt; with the &lt;code&gt;location&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;timeslot&lt;/code&gt; pre-populated in the body. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send the email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/workflow-1.png&quot;&gt; 
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Creating the workflow&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/workflow-2.png&quot;&gt; 
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Entering a 60-minute window&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/workflow-3.png&quot;&gt; 
&lt;figcaption&gt;The compose sheet if more info is necessary&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/workflow-7.png&quot;&gt; 
&lt;figcaption&gt;Putting the &amp;lsquo;app&amp;rsquo; on the home screen&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How to use it.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With one tap from my iPhone or iPad, I can now instantly update USADA with my current whereabouts and a new 60-minute time slot, all without writing an email or opening Maps. I tap on the icon, add my 60 minute window from the picker, and the rest happens automatically. If I need to add additional details to the email, I can adjust the workflow to show the &amp;lsquo;Compose Sheet&amp;rsquo;, but I normally just let Workflow send the email instantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updating is even easier on the Apple Watch. I open Workflow, press the &amp;lsquo;Update USADA&amp;rsquo; button, and I&amp;rsquo;m done. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/worklow-4.jpg&quot;&gt; 
&lt;figcaption&gt;Launching from Apple Watch&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;shot&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/workflow-5.jpg&quot;&gt; 
&lt;figcaption&gt;Getting the location&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;shot&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/workflow-6.jpg&quot;&gt; 
&lt;figcaption&gt;Sending the email&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you a USADA athlete with an iOS device? &lt;a href=&quot;https://workflow.is/workflows/a63ae7a9649f48dda111b2c4d917198c&quot;&gt;Download my &lt;em&gt;Update USADA&lt;/em&gt; workflow&lt;/a&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll need the Workflow app to use it.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;

&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My biggest criticism of the app is that it was clearly built with a cross-platform solution such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://xamarin.com&quot;&gt;Xamarin&lt;/a&gt; to make it available for Android and iOS. The proposed benefit is a single codebase that works on both platforms, but the result is often a mess that isn&amp;rsquo;t optimized for either. The resulting crashes and conflicts with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/UserExperience/Conceptual/MobileHIG/&quot;&gt;iOS Human Interface Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; demonstrate the latter.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref1&quot; rev=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 2015</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/newsletter/june-2015</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 09:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/newsletter/june-2015</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just returned from our annual USA Bobsled/Skeleton Team Camp in Colorado Springs, CO. I managed to resist the lure of in-flight WiFi, so I was able to catch up on a ton of reading. Flying presents a great opportunity to binge read &amp;ndash; if you aren&amp;rsquo;t glued to the window like I usually am. But the window held me captive for a different reason this trip. My flight was greatly enhanced by the writing of 747 pilot Mark Vanhoenacker, whose brilliant debut book tops my recommendations this month. But before we get to the books, I have a quick request. If you know someone who might enjoy my recommendations, please forward this email to them. It would mean a lot to me! And remember, you can always reach out to me with questions or recommendations of your own. Just reply directly to this email. Now let&amp;rsquo;s get to the books!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1ejk4bT&quot;&gt;Skyfaring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Mark Vanhoenacker&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself boarding a plane this summer, buy this book and read it on the flight. Vanhoenacker can &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; write. He&amp;rsquo;s one of the most original voices I&amp;rsquo;ve read in a long time. Skyfaring defies categorization. It&amp;rsquo;s a love letter to aviation, but it&amp;rsquo;s more poetic than technical. Even if you aren&amp;rsquo;t a fan of flying, Skyfaring is worth your time. This is a brilliant debut book that&amp;rsquo;s already in the running for my favorite book of the year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1LUW6yR&quot;&gt;Tomorrowland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Steven Kotler&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read everything Kotler has written, from &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1ejkPBE&quot;&gt;The Rise of Superman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; to his excellent collaborations with Peter Diamandis (&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1LUWAF9&quot;&gt;Abundance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1LDi0so&quot;&gt;Bold&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;). Tomorrowland is about science fiction turned fact. With short chapters on topics like asteroid mining. genetic engineering, and bionic implants, the future is arriving. Kotler has written an excellent guide on what to expect when it gets here. Pair with &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1GO9JfM&quot;&gt;The Physics of the Future&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; by Michio Kaku for a deeper look. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1GOa9m9&quot;&gt;On the Shortness of Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Seneca&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bring a physical copy of this book with me when I travel, partly because it&amp;rsquo;s such a short book, but mostly because I learn something new every time I read it. I find Seneca to be the most interesting of the Stoics. He lived during a dangerous time, in an empire governed by a megalomaniacal tyrant. Though we may never know the &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; Seneca, especially in regard to his role in Nero&amp;rsquo;s crimes, his work has survived the centuries because it is packed with incredible insight into the art of living. &amp;ldquo;Life is long if you know how to use it&amp;rdquo;. For more on the life of Seneca, check out &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1ejlAL8&quot;&gt;Dying Every Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; by James Romm. It reads more like historical fiction than straight history. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1FRjpEz&quot;&gt;Jurassic Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Michael Crichton&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist. With Jurassic World ruling the box office, I had to reread the book that started it all. The last time I read this book was in 2008 on a long drive between Calgary and Salt Lake City. I remember being amazed by how much more violent it was was compared to its PG-13 counterpart. Mostly I was impressed by Chrichton&amp;rsquo;s ability to blend hard science with fast-paced storytelling. My rereading didn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint, and if you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet read Jurassic Park, now is a good time. It&amp;rsquo;s a great beach book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great July. Until next month,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kyle&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May 2015</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/newsletter/may-2015</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 09:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/newsletter/may-2015</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;May was a busy month, but I still managed to read some terrific books. If like me, you&amp;rsquo;re finding it hard to make time to read, here&amp;rsquo;s a quick tip. Choose a manageable number of pages to read each day and turn it into a daily habit. 20 pages is a good place to start, and it adds up to 36 books a year. That&amp;rsquo;s a lot of reading, and it&amp;rsquo;s a great investment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there was a loose theme to my reading this month, it&amp;#39;s changing the world. From the invention of the airplane to the emergence of Sapiens, these books demonstrate our species&amp;#39; tendency to push beyond boundaries and shape the world according to our desires &amp;ndash; for better and worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1KGhnik&quot;&gt;The Wright Brothers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;em&gt;David McCullough&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think McCullough is one of the best popular history writers of all time. His biography of &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1Fnn5Pi&quot;&gt;John Adams&lt;/a&gt; is incredible, and it formed the basis of the equally impressive HBO series starring Paul Giamatti. The Wright Brothers is the latest in a long list of bestsellers for the two-time ulitzer winner. It&amp;rsquo;s a vivid account of the birth of powered flight &amp;ndash; not a history of airplanes, but of the two brilliant bicycle mechanics who willed them into existence through sheer intellect and unwavering commitment. If you fly a lot like I do, you&amp;rsquo;ll appreciate this book, even more so the next time you&amp;rsquo;re &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/uEY58fiSK8E?t=2m&quot;&gt;sitting in a chair in the sky&lt;/a&gt; browsing the web at 36,000 feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1EIXXB2&quot;&gt;How Adam Smith Can Change Your Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Russ Roberts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d heard good things about this book, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until I picked it up in a bookstore and read the introduction that I decided to buy it. Roberts is a popular economist (check out his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.econtalk.org/&quot;&gt;EconTalk podcast&lt;/a&gt;), but he didn&amp;rsquo;t read The Wealth of Nations or the long-neglected Theory of Moral Sentiments until late in his career. He was so impressed by the latter that he decided to write this book. With chapter titles like &amp;lsquo;How to be Happy&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;How to be Good&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;lsquo;How to Make the World a Better Place&amp;rsquo;,  it&amp;rsquo;s a quick and enjoyable introduction to a forgotten classic. Whether you decide to read The Theory of Moral Sentiments or not, definitely check this book out. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1KwxjQO&quot;&gt;Sapiens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Yuval Noah Harari&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;100,000 years ago there were at least 6 species of humans on the planet, yet today we are the sole survivors. Why? That&amp;rsquo;s the central question of Harari&amp;rsquo;s book, billed as a brief history of humankind. It&amp;rsquo;s a whirlwind tour through the whole of our history, focusing on our major revolutions: cognitive, agricultural, and scientific. Sapiens will forever alter your opinion of what happens when humans arrive in an environment (in short, we destroy it), and it concludes with a speculative look into the future of our species. This is a stunning work and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to read more from Harari in the future. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1KGhRVC&quot;&gt;Zero to One&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Peter Theil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter Theil - cofounder of PayPal and Palantir, President of Clarium Capitol, and first outside investor in Facebook - knows a thing or two about starting companies. In Zero to One he argues that most businesses take the world from 1 to N. They add a little value to a familiar idea. As someone who was once approached to build &amp;ldquo;Facebook for pets&amp;rdquo;, I can attest to this. But occasionally a company creates something completely new and takes the world from 0 to 1. As Theil says in the introduction, &amp;ldquo;the next Larry Page and Sergei Brin won&amp;rsquo;t make a search engine. And the next Mark Zuckerberg won&amp;rsquo;t create a social network&amp;rdquo;. We can do better than a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yo_(app)&quot;&gt;Yo! app&lt;/a&gt;, and this book is a call to do so.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just celebrated my 34th(!) birthday, and I received a ton of books that I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to read and share with you. If you want to say hi or tell me about a book you enjoyed, please do! I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear from you, and all you have to do is reply to this email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re awesome. Until next month, &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kyle&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
