<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Kyle Tress</title>
    <link>http://kyletress.com</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 16:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>Madness</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/home/madness</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 09:43:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/home/madness</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re only given a little spark of madness. You mustn&amp;rsquo;t lose it&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Robin Williams&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are your combine scores?</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/what-are-your-combine-scores</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 21:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/what-are-your-combine-scores</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are my scores from the summer of 2013. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Event&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;2013&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15m&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.18s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;30m&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.90s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;45m&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.62s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;30m Fly&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.35s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Broad Jump&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.25m&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Underhand shot toss&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16.40m&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Power Clean&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;130kg&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Back Squat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;160kg&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much longer will you compete?</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/how-much-longer-will-you-compete</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 20:58:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/how-much-longer-will-you-compete</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The best answer I can give is &lt;em&gt;at least through 2018&lt;/em&gt;. Skeleton athletes can be competitive into their 40s. I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; saying I will be, but it&amp;rsquo;s possible. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is your best World Cup finish?</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/what-is-your-best-world-cup-finish</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 20:57:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/what-is-your-best-world-cup-finish</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a tie: 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; in Lake Placid (2013) and St. Moritz (2014).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When should I buy my first sled?</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/when-should-i-buy-my-first-sled</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 17:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/when-should-i-buy-my-first-sled</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I advise people to wait at least &lt;em&gt;one full season&lt;/em&gt; before purchasing equipment. Most people ignore this advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I recommend you wait is because you won&amp;rsquo;t have any clue what you&amp;rsquo;re doing your first year. You&amp;rsquo;ll probably have 2-3 months of time on the track, and you might take 10-15 runs per week. This time should be dedicated to building awareness, perfecting your form, getting a feel for the track, and soaking up as much knowledge as you can from the coaches. Messing around with equipment to try and go faster isn&amp;rsquo;t a priority yet. Plus, any sled you buy will likely be too sensitive for your abilities. The same goes with runners.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What kind of training should I be doing?</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/what-kind-of-training-should-i-be-doing</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 17:02:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/what-kind-of-training-should-i-be-doing</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recommend you find a good sprint coach, as speed development is probably the most important training for skeleton. If you&amp;rsquo;re in high school, join the track team. Otherwise, ask around at local colleges and find a coach you can train with once or twice per week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strength is important too. You will need to focus on major lifts like squats and presses. Familiarizing yourself with the Olympic lifts (like the power clean) and get help if necessary. Proper form is important. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How long before I make the National Team?</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/how-long-before-i-make-the-national-team</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 16:58:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/how-long-before-i-make-the-national-team</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The National Team consists of the top 5 or 6 men and women in the United States. It used to be larger, but has been narrowed down in recent years. It may take several seasons to make the National Team, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you won&amp;rsquo;t be racing in competitive events. The development team travels throughout North America and Europe as well, and occasionally bumps up to higher circuits throughout the season. The development circuits are a great place to learn the sport and the tracks so you will be ready to compete when you make the team.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which track is the most difficult?</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/which-track-is-the-hardest</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 16:06:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/which-track-is-the-hardest</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Difficulty is subjective. There are many athletes who find Lake Placid challenging, but because I learned how to slide here and have 2000 runs on the track, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t call it difficult. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had to choose, I&amp;rsquo;d say Altenberg and Whistler are two of the hardest tracks in the world. But most tracks are difficult in their own ways, maybe not in terms of safely getting to the bottom, but doing it fast. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which supplements do you take?</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/which-supplements-do-you-take</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 02:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/which-supplements-do-you-take</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mandatory disclaimer&lt;/em&gt;: Consult your doctor first and all that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.musclepharm.com&quot;&gt;MusclePharm products&lt;/a&gt;. I use Combat (protein), Assault (preworkout), and Recon (postworkout). I also take creatine monohydrate, caffeine, vitamin D, fish oil, ZMA (nightime recovery), and the occasional multivitamin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How has skeleton changed your life?</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/how-has-skeleton-changed-your-life</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 02:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/how-has-skeleton-changed-your-life</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In more ways than I could mention. Everything fell into place when I saw skeleton for the first time. Prior to that, I was directionless. I dropped in and out of school, played in a band, and considered pursuing a career as an actor. After seeing skeleton, I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to read about it, or research it, I just knew it was &lt;em&gt;it&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skeleton pushed me in ways I never expected. It taught me to appreciate hard work, because that&amp;rsquo;s the reward. It allowed me to travel the world. It introduced me to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.morgantracey.us&quot;&gt;my girlfriend&lt;/a&gt; and two of my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mattantoine.com&quot;&gt;best&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/johndalyusa&quot;&gt;friends&lt;/a&gt;. It gave me &lt;a href=&quot;/skeleton/sochi&quot;&gt;one of the greatest moments in my life&lt;/a&gt;, and enough memories and friendships to last a lifetime. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also hated to fly. Now, with 20+ flights per year, it&amp;rsquo;s one of my favorite things to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is one thing that skeleton has taught you?</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/what-is-one-thing-that-skeleton-has-taught-you</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 02:28:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/what-is-one-thing-that-skeleton-has-taught-you</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Patience. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What's your proudest accomplishment?</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/whats-your-proudest-accomplishment</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 02:16:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/whats-your-proudest-accomplishment</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Competing in the Olympic Games is the obvious choice. I&amp;rsquo;m also proud of being named the 2005 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rpmfund.org&quot;&gt;Randy Price Memorial Award Winner&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m honored to be a three-time winner of the Athlete&amp;rsquo;s Choice Award. But no one will ever say it better than Olympic Champion Curt Thomasevic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My proudest accomplishment in bobsled isn’t two Olympic medals. It is knowing that after 10 years, no one can ever question my commitment, my honor, or my character and intentions. I did my best to make myself and my teammates better every day. I had an experience that no one can ever take away. And I don’t need an Olympic medal to remind me of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the combine?</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/what-is-the-combine</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 02:09:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/what-is-the-combine</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The combine is a standardized test to measure speed, power, and strength of bobsled and skeleton athletes. There are three tiers. If you are a brand new skeleton athlete (tier 1), you will be asked to take three 45m sprints through timing eyes. From the timing data, the coaches will get 15, 30, flying 30, and 45 meter sprint times. Then you will be asked to do an underhand shot toss and a standing broad jump. Your score will be calculated according to a points table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most current athletes (Tier 2) also complete a weight room portion, including a 3RM back squat and a 1RM clean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tier 3 athletes are those who have competed in an Olympic Games or World Championships in the past two years. Tier 3 athletes don&amp;rsquo;t take a formal combine, but are instead monitored through their strength and conditioning coaches. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How expensive is it to build a track?</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/how-expensive-is-it-to-make-a-track</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 22:21:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/how-expensive-is-it-to-make-a-track</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Modern combined bobsled/skeleton/luge facilities are expensive affairs, costing millions, sometimes &lt;em&gt;hundreds&lt;/em&gt; of millions, to build. The Whistler Sliding Centre had a price tag of $105MM CAD, and rumor has it the Sanki Sliding Centre in Sochi cost substantially more. I&amp;rsquo;d love to see more natural tracks  like the one in St. Moritz, Switzerland, but the knowledge and experience to build them is highly specialized. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have you competed on every track?</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/have-you-competed-on-every-track</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 22:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/have-you-competed-on-every-track</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Of the tracks still in use, I haven&amp;rsquo;t been to Sigulda, Lillehammer, Paramanovo, and Nagano. I think the Germans slide in Oberhof, but it&amp;rsquo;s not really used otherwise.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which countries have skeleton tracks?</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/which-countries-have-skeleton-tracks</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 22:04:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/which-countries-have-skeleton-tracks</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;USA, Canada, Germany, Austria, Italy, France, Norway, Japan, Russia, Switzerland, Latvia, and soon Korea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do you train in the winter?</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/how-do-you-train-in-the-winter</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 21:57:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/how-do-you-train-in-the-winter</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The winter is focused almost entirely on sliding and equipment prep, but we do make time for sprinting and lifting. We travel with a squat rack, weights, and a bench. We make use of local running tracks where we can find them. We lug 10lb bags of protein through airport security. it&amp;rsquo;s not pretty, but it works. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sliding usually lasts a few hours. We often spend extra time watching athletes from other nations and walking the track, and we have a nightly meeting and video review session. Equipment preparation takes another hour or so. When you factor in time for sports medicine and recovery, the days are pretty full. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is skeleton easy?</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/is-skeleton-easy</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 21:48:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/is-skeleton-easy</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Skeleton is not a easy by any stretch of the imagination. It challenges you mentally and physically. It requires strength and power. It requires skill and experience. It&amp;rsquo;s a technical sport. It&amp;rsquo;s a feeling sport. It&amp;rsquo;s all these things and more. Oh, and it&amp;rsquo;s a damn &lt;em&gt;expensive&lt;/em&gt; sport, too. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the myth that skeleton is easy comes from an article published by Rick Reilly a few years ago in Sports Illustrated. Rick took a cheap shot at us because he probably saw an easy target. We called him out on it, offered him a chance to come up to Lake Placid and try skeleton for free, courtesy of the United States skeleton team. Not the tourist version of skeleton - but the &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; sport, from the top of the track - 80 miles per hour, headfirst. Rick definitely got the invite, but we never heard from him. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rick, the offer still stands. Bring extra pads.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I get started?</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/how-do-i-get-started</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 21:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/how-do-i-get-started</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is probably the most common question I get, so I wrote a full post about it. In short, you should contact your National Governing Body, which in the US is &lt;em&gt;The United States Bobsled and Skeleton Federation&lt;/em&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll probably sign up for a combine test, and if you do well you&amp;rsquo;ll be invited to Lake Placid for a skeleton school. If you enjoy the sport and the coaches like what they see, you&amp;rsquo;ll enter our development pipeline and be on your way.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What's it like going 90 miles per hour headfirst?</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/whats-it-like-going-90-miles-per-hour-headfirst</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 21:26:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/skeleton/faqs/whats-it-like-going-90-miles-per-hour-headfirst</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I imagine it&amp;rsquo;s different for every athlete, but for me it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;peaceful&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a minute of pure focus for my otherwise scattered and ADD brain. For 60 blissful seconds I have absolutely nothing else in the world to worry about. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also exhilirating and addicting, but if you&amp;rsquo;re reading this you probably already knew that. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
