<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Kyle Tress</title>
    <link>http://kyletress.com</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 03:26:58 -0400</pubDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Apollo Flew to the Moon</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/how-apollo-flew-to-the-moon</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 03:25:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/how-apollo-flew-to-the-moon</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk-5</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 14:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk-5</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had anyone from Detroit stopped by Tesla Motors at this point, they would have ended up in hysterics. The sum total of the company&amp;rsquo;s automotive expertise was that a couple of the guys at Tesla really liked cars and another one had created a series of science fair projects based on technology that the automotive industry considered ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk-4</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 01:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk-4</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You always feel particularly good when the wheels lift off in Moscow,&amp;rdquo; Cantrell said. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s like, &amp;lsquo;My God. I made it.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk-3</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 01:21:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk-3</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Musk&amp;rsquo;s first interactions with the Aeronautics community were with an eclectic collection of space enthusiasts, members of a nonprofit group called the Mars Society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk-2</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 00:36:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Musk fell into the classic self-taught coder trap of writing what developers call hairballs – big, monolithic hunks of code that could go berserk for mysterious reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk-1</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 21:11:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk-1</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Elon gets into something, he develops just this different level of interest in it than other people. That is what differentiates Elon from the rest of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 01:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/notes/elon-musk</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think there are probably too many smart people pursuing Internet stuff, finance, and law. That is part of the reason why we haven&amp;rsquo;t seen as much innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/elon-musk</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2015 15:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/elon-musk</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Man on the Moon</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/a-man-on-the-moon</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2015 15:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/a-man-on-the-moon</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Right Stuff</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/the-right-stuff</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2015 15:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/the-right-stuff</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Case for Mars</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/the-case-for-mars</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 23:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/the-case-for-mars</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crooked</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/crooked</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 14:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/crooked</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A hilarious re-telling of Richard Nixon&amp;rsquo;s life &amp;ndash; with a supernatural twist. I&amp;rsquo;m a sucker for presidential biographies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Armada</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/armada</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 14:25:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/armada</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I loved &lt;em&gt;Ready Player One&lt;/em&gt;, so I bought &lt;em&gt;Armada&lt;/em&gt; without a second thought. It&amp;rsquo;s a fast, fun read without much substance. Not my favorite, but it&amp;rsquo;s an enjoyable summer read. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/cdp/member-reviews/ANLVSN1MTGE9D/ref=pdp_new_read_full_review_link?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;page=1&amp;amp;sort_by=MostRecentReview#R33QHX5T591QA2&quot;&gt;My Amazon review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I use Apple Watch</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/essays/how-i-use-apple-watch</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 20:11:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/essays/how-i-use-apple-watch</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bought an Apple Watch on launch day, and since then I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten a lot of questions about it. Besides the battery life (which is way better than expected), the most common question is &amp;ldquo;what does it do?&amp;rdquo;. People want to know how the Apple Watch would fit into their lives. Inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@dmitribilgere/things-i-have-done-with-my-apple-watch-d7d31b289972&quot;&gt;this post by Dmitir Bilgier&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted to write about the main ways I&amp;rsquo;ve used my Apple Watch so far. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile boarding pass&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; On a recent trip to Colorado, I used it to go through security and to check-in at the gate. Only once did I have problems scanning the QR code. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t scan at the gate in Chicago and I had to dig for my phone, holding up the line. Sorry folks. That aside, it made the airport experience more pleasant. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timing flights&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; 
The crew says the flight is going to be 2 hours and 30 minutes. Sounds great. What time did we leave again? How much longer do we have? What time zone am I going to? I timed all my flights takeoff to touchdown so I knew exactly how much flight time was remaining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hey, Siri&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; I was a pretty regular Siri user before the Watch.  Now I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine living without it. I&amp;rsquo;m constantly asking Siri for directions, phone numbers, upcoming appointments, and reminders. Simply raising your wrist and saying &amp;ldquo;Hey Siri&amp;rdquo; activates it, which is great if you&amp;rsquo;re driving and need directions. I&amp;rsquo;ve also noticed a new feature: The &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; Siri is kind of a smart ass. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple Pay&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; Using Apple Pay on the iPhone is fun. Using it on the watch is extraordinary. I still get excited to pay with Apple Watch, if only to see the cashier&amp;rsquo;s reaction. I&amp;rsquo;ve had several tell me I&amp;rsquo;m the first to do so at their store. It feels like living in the future.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daily reminder alarms&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;m a notoriously bad eater. I have no problem eating once per day, performance effects be damned. Paired with medication that further reduces my appetite, I have to be diligent about my eating habits. I set seven daily alarms on repeat Monday - Friday to remind me to eat. Overkill? Yeah probably, but it works.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updating USADA&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; I wrote about my need to &lt;a href=&quot;/essays/usada-workflow&quot;&gt;update USADA&lt;/a&gt; on a regular basis. I automated the process with Workflow. No need to get my location or write an email. One tap and I&amp;rsquo;m done, right from the watch.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notify me to film my 1SE&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;ve been filming one second every day since 2013. Some days I forget. I allow 1SE to notify me once per day, and I immediately shoot whatever is happening at that moment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control my Apple TV&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; Using the watch as a remote is actually  easier than using the &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; Apple TV remote. I hate that thing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weather station&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; Dark Sky notifies me up to an hour before light or heavy rain. I often ride my bike to training, so this is really helpful. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Music&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; The watch has a few gigs set aside for music storage. Since the release of Apple Music, I&amp;rsquo;ve started to take advantage of this by syncing playlists directly to it and pairing it with my Beats headphones. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to warmup and workout without risking my iPhone hitting the ground.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Track and time my workout&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; One of the main reasons I bought the watch was to time my workouts (rest between sets, tempo runs, etc). Any watch could fill this role, but I like having a dedicated heart rate monitor, step counter, calorie counter, etc. The watch will almost certainly gain additional sensors over time, making it more useful in this capacity. One nitpick &amp;ndash; there is no option for setting seconds in the timer. To get a 30-second timer, you have to ask Siri.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quickly respond to messages&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how often I can respond to a message right from the watch. It&amp;rsquo;s smart, and will vary the suggested responses based on the message received. And if that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work there&amp;rsquo;s always dictation or an emoji :) .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Silent notifications&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; Probably my favorite, and the most unsung, feature of the Apple Watch is a return to blissful silence. No more chimes, beeps, or ringtones. I feel a gentle tap on my wrist when a notification arrives, and I carefully control which get through. Before the watch I&amp;rsquo;d hear three notifications for the same incoming message: one from my iPhone, one from my iPad, and another from my Mac. That drove me crazy, especially when silencing them wasn&amp;rsquo;t an option. Now everything is on silent all the time, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about missing truly important notifications. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granted, my iPhone could do nearly everything above, but the benefit of the Apple Watch is &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; it accomplishes these tasks. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t cover everything for the sake of brevity. Suffice it to say I&amp;rsquo;m finding new uses every day. It&amp;rsquo;s made a positive impact on my life, and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to see what developers do with native apps and watchOS 2. Wearables are here, and Apple is leading the way. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A workflow for updating USADA</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/essays/usada-workflow</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 16:13:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/essays/usada-workflow</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an Olympian, I&amp;rsquo;m subject to frequent random drug testing by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usada.org&quot;&gt;United States Anti-Doping Administration&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m in the &lt;em&gt;International Testing Pool&lt;/em&gt;, which means I&amp;rsquo;m required to provide USADA with a daily 60-minute time slot. Though technically I can be tested at any time, I &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; be at my designated location during this 60-minute window or I&amp;rsquo;ll receive a missed test. Three missed tests in a 12-month period could result in a ban, so it&amp;rsquo;s important that I&amp;rsquo;m diligent with my updates. The problem is I&amp;rsquo;m not always diligent, and I imagine other athletes aren&amp;rsquo;t either. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of ways to update USADA, but by far the easiest is to send an email to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:update@usada.org&quot;&gt;update@usada.org&lt;/a&gt;. Most of my teammates set a blanket 60-minute time slot for the entire quarter, then update via email as their plans change. This is simple and easy, but not without its inconveniences. First, it&amp;rsquo;s annoying to have to write the same email every time. Second, I might not have the address at my location. As a developer, I saw an opportunity to remove some of the headache and repetition for myself and other athletes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;USADA has a mobile app, but it frequently crashes and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to use&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Their website isn&amp;rsquo;t much better. There&amp;rsquo;s no public API, so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t create my own app. I wanted the simplicity of email updates with the convenience of a &amp;lsquo;native&amp;rsquo; mobile app. Enter &lt;a href=&quot;https://workflow.is&quot;&gt;Workflow&lt;/a&gt;.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Workflow App&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Workflow is an app that bills itself as &amp;lsquo;powerful automation made simple&amp;rsquo;. Federico Viticci of MacStories.net wrote &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macstories.net/reviews/workflow-review-integrated-automation-for-ios-8/&quot;&gt;a terrific review of Workflow&lt;/a&gt;, so I won&amp;rsquo;t retread that ground here. Suffice it to say, Workflow makes it possible to automate repetitive tasks by taking advantage of native iOS functionality. A workflow can be saved on the home screen of your device and act as its own little native app. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Update USADA Workflow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given my requirements, setting up the workflow was easy. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get the current location and save it as a variable &lt;code&gt;location&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask the user for a 60-minute time slot, and save it as &lt;code&gt;timeslot&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create an email to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:update@usada.org&quot;&gt;update@usada.org&lt;/a&gt; with the &lt;code&gt;location&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;timeslot&lt;/code&gt; pre-populated in the body. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send the email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/workflow-1.png&quot;&gt; 
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Creating the workflow&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/workflow-2.png&quot;&gt; 
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Entering a 60-minute window&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/workflow-3.png&quot;&gt; 
&lt;figcaption&gt;The compose sheet if more info is necessary&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/workflow-7.png&quot;&gt; 
&lt;figcaption&gt;Putting the &amp;lsquo;app&amp;rsquo; on the home screen&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How to use it.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With one tap from my iPhone or iPad, I can now instantly update USADA with my current whereabouts and a new 60-minute time slot, all without writing an email or opening Maps. I tap on the icon, add my 60 minute window from the picker, and the rest happens automatically. If I need to add additional details to the email, I can adjust the workflow to show the &amp;lsquo;Compose Sheet&amp;rsquo;, but I normally just let Workflow send the email instantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updating is even easier on the Apple Watch. I open Workflow, press the &amp;lsquo;Update USADA&amp;rsquo; button, and I&amp;rsquo;m done. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/worklow-4.jpg&quot;&gt; 
&lt;figcaption&gt;Launching from Apple Watch&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;shot&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/workflow-5.jpg&quot;&gt; 
&lt;figcaption&gt;Getting the location&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;shot&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/workflow-6.jpg&quot;&gt; 
&lt;figcaption&gt;Sending the email&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you a USADA athlete with an iOS device? &lt;a href=&quot;https://workflow.is/workflows/a63ae7a9649f48dda111b2c4d917198c&quot;&gt;Download my &lt;em&gt;Update USADA&lt;/em&gt; workflow&lt;/a&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll need the Workflow app to use it.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;

&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My biggest criticism of the app is that it was clearly built with a cross-platform solution such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://xamarin.com&quot;&gt;Xamarin&lt;/a&gt; to make it available for Android and iOS. The proposed benefit is a single codebase that works on both platforms, but the result is often a mess that isn&amp;rsquo;t optimized for either. The resulting crashes and conflicts with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/UserExperience/Conceptual/MobileHIG/&quot;&gt;iOS Human Interface Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; demonstrate the latter.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref1&quot; rev=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sapiens</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/sapiens</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 00:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/sapiens</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A whirlwind tour through the history of humanity focusing on our 3 major revolutions: cognitive, agricultural, and scientific. Sapiens will forever alter your opinion of what happens when humans arrive in an environment (we  basically destroy it), and it concludes with a speculative look into the future of our species.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wright Brothers</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/the-wright-brothers</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 22:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/the-wright-brothers</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think David McCullough is one of the finest popular history writers of our time. With &lt;em&gt;The Wright Brothers&lt;/em&gt; he has delivered a rich account of the birth of powered flight. But this isn&amp;rsquo;t a book about airplanes &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s a biography of the two bicycle mechanics who willed them into existence through sheer intellect and unwavering commitment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Adam Smith Can Change Your Life</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/how-adam-smith-can-change-your-life</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 14:37:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/how-adam-smith-can-change-your-life</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With chapters on &amp;lsquo;How to be Happy&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;How to be Good&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;lsquo;How to Make the World a Better Place&amp;rsquo;, this is a quick and enjoyable introduction to Adam Smith&amp;rsquo;s forgotten classic. Whether you decide to read The Theory of Moral Sentiments or not, definitely check this book out. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/cdp/member-reviews/ANLVSN1MTGE9D/ref=pdp_new_read_full_review_link?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;page=1&amp;amp;sort_by=MostRecentReview#R1LA3WQ16NT39L&quot;&gt;My Amazon review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero To One</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/zero-to-one</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 14:36:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/zero-to-one</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As Theil says, &amp;ldquo;the next Larry Page and Sergei Brin won&amp;rsquo;t make a search engine. And the next Mark Zuckerberg won&amp;rsquo;t create a social network&amp;rdquo;. Most businesses take the world from 1 to N. this is a book about building something completely new and taking the world from 0 to 1.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resilience</title>
      <link>http://kyletress.com/reading/resilience</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 18:29:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Tress</author>
      <guid>http://kyletress.com/reading/resilience</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Greitens is a Navy SEAL, Rhode Scholar, author of the New York Times Bestseller &lt;em&gt;The Heart and the Fist&lt;/em&gt;, and candidate for Governor of Missouri. Here he offers something reminiscent of Seneca. Resilience is presented as a series of letters between Greitens and a former SEAL teammate who is suffering from PTSD. Like Seneca, this is a book worth dipping into from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
